He saw wrong and tried to right it. He saw suffering and tried
to heal it. He saw war and tried to stop it.
Bobby is a drama film directed by Emilio Estevez.
In 1968 the lives of a retired doorman, hotel manager, lounge singer,
busboy, beautician and others intersect in the wake of Robert F.
Kennedy's assassination at the Ambassador Hotel in Los Angeles.
John Casey, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Paul Ebbers, played by William H. Macy.
Nelson, played by Harry Belafonte.
José Rojas, played by Freddy Rodríguez.
Edward Robinson, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Angela, played by Heather Graham.
Bobby is a 2006 American drama film written and directed by Emilio Estevez, and starring an ensemble cast featuring Harry Belafonte, Joy Bryant, Nick
Cannon, Laurence Fishburne, Spencer Garrett, Helen Hunt, Joshua Jackson, Anthony Hopkins, Ashton Kutcher, Shia LaBeouf, Lindsay Lohan, William H.
Macy, Demi Moore, Martin Sheen, Christian Slater, Sharon Stone, Freddy Rodriguez, Heather
Graham, Mary Elizabeth Winstead, Elijah Wood, David Krumholtz and Estevez.
The screenplay is a fictionalized account of the hours
leading up to the June 5, 1968, shooting of U.S.
Senator Robert F.
Kennedy in the kitchen of the Ambassador Hotel in Los Angeles following his
victory in the 1968 Democratic presidential primary in California.
The film was produced by The Weinstein Company and Bold Films and distributed by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (through MGM Distribution Co.) and
premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14, 2006 before being released theatrically on November 17, 2006.
The film received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of hotel, politics, marriage
crisis, senator, los angeles, california.
The tone is emotional.